Guide to the David Low Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1900-66; Series IV; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  - PERSONAL PRESS CLIPPINGS
    - Loose Clippings
      - 1920s, 1920-27, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1100)
      - 1930s, 1931-39, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1101)
      - 1940s, part I, 1940-45 (Box 32, Folder 1102)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 1286
      - 1940s, part II, 1946-49, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1103)
      - 1950s, part I, 1950-52 (Box 33, Folder 1104)
      - 1950s, part II, 1953-59 (Box 33, Folder 1105)
      - 1950s, part III, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1106)
      - 1960s, 1960-63, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1107)
      - No date, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1108)
  - PRINTED MATERIALS, MISCELLANEOUS
    - Air Raid Precautions Materials, part I, 1940s (Box 33, Folder 1109)
      See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 1317
    - Art and architecture (Box 33, Folder 1110)
    - Labor organizations, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1111)
    - Peace organizations, 1948-53, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1112)
    - Political organizations, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1113)
    - Miscellany, 1939-61, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1114)
  - SCRAPBOOKS
    - Scrapbook, 1930s (Box 33, Folder 1115)
  - WORKS ON LOW
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folders 1201-06; Box 40, folders 1287-91; Box 41, folders 1292-1316
    - B., A. A., "Low of the 'Star'": printed version, 1926 May (Box 33, Folder 1116)
    - Barry, Gerald, "David Low--British Cartoonist": typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1117)
    - Barry, Gerald, "Genius of David Low," The Hindu: printed version, 1949 Nov 2 (Box 33, Folder 1118)
    - Bordages, Asa, "Famous Briton Lists 6 Great U. S. Figures, but Tantalizingly Refuses to Name Them," New York World- Telegram: printed version, 1936 Oct 26 (Box 33, Folder 1119)
    - Bradish, C. R., "David Low: London's Premier Cartoonist Who Still Adheres to the Impertinence of Holding Views," The Home: printed version, 1931 Mar 2 (Box 33, Folder 1120)
    - Brown, W. J., "Sack Me? That from the Unsackable !," Evening Citizen: printed version, 1949 Nov 1 (Box 33, Folder 1121-22)
    - "Cartoonist with a Mission," News Review: printed version, 1950 Feb 2 (Box 33, Folder 1123)
    - Cohen, Chapman, "Views and Opinions," The Freethinker: printed version, 1942 Mar 15 (Box 33, Folder 1124)
    - "Colonel Blimp and His Creator," Age: printed version, 1943 May 1 (Box 33, Folder 1125)
    - Cowie, Donald, "Low: An Interview": printed version, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1126)
    - "David Low--Caricaturist," Stead's Review: printed version, 1919 Mar 8 (Box 33, Folder 1127)
    - Driberg, Tom, "Unobtrusive Iconoclast: David Low, a Nuisance Dedicated to Sanity," The English Digest: printed version, condensed, 1945 Nov (Box 33, Folder 1128)
    - Gammans, L. D., "King of the Blimps?," Evening Standard: printed version, 1944 Feb 2 (Box 33, Folder 1129)
    - Guttmann, Henry, "My War against Hitler": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1130)
    - Horabin, J. F., "The Greatest of Cartoonists," The New Leader: printed version, 1931 Feb 6 (Box 33, Folder 1131)
    - Lawlor, Pat, "The Early Drawings of David Low," The Turnbull Library Record: printed version, 1941 Jul-Dec (Box 33, Folder 1132)
    - Legum, Colin, "An Interview with David Low," New Era: printed version, 1952 Jul 6 (Box 33, Folder 1133)
    - Low, Caroline, "Low's First Studio in the Fowlhouse," Lyttelton Times: printed version, 1928 Sep 15 (Box 33, Folder 1134)
    - "Low, the Cartoonist": printed version, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1135)
    - Nelson, Wallace, "After Business Hours: Caricatures and Caricaturists, with Reminiscences of David Low," The Australasian Manufacturer: printed version, 1936 Sep 19 (Box 33, Folder 1136)
    - Nicolson, Harold, "Marginal Comment," The Spectator: printed version, 1942 Mar 6 (Box 33, Folder 1137)
    - Potter, Stephen, "Low: An Impression of a Great Caricaturist" [radio script]: typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Apr 24 (Box 33, Folder 1138)
    - Pyle, Ernie, "Greatest Cartoonist: Low Also Bomb Watcher," New York World- Telegram: printed version, 1941 Mar 31 (Box 33, Folder 1139)
    - R., A. W., "A Talk with Low: New Zealand's Famous Cartoonist," The New Zealand News: printed version, 1930 Jul 15 (Box 33, Folder 1140)
    - "Settled Cartoonists," The New Yorker: printed version, 1948 Jun 12 (Box 33, Folder 1141)
    - "Sketches by Dan 28--Mr. David Low": printed version, 1937 Oct 23 (Box 33, Folder 1142)
    - Somerset, W. A., "David Low on Cartooning": printed version, 1919 Oct 1 (Box 33, Folder 1143)
    - Streicher, Lawrence H., "David Low and the Mass Press": reprint, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 1144)
    - Streicher, Lawrence H., "David Low and the Sociology of Caricature": reprint, 1965 Oct (Box 33, Folder 1145)
    - Vallette, Jacques, "Trois cents dessins de Low," Le Monde: printed version, 1950 Dec 29 (Box 33, Folder 1146)
    - Webber, Nevile, "'Cartooning Is a Serious Business': David Low Explains Why He Left Lord Beaverbrook,"
      - Herald: printed version, 1950 Feb 17 (Box 33, Folder 1147)
      - The Press: printed version, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1148)
    - Wilkinson, Ellen, "Low's Cartoons," All About Books: printed version, 1931 Jan 19 (Box 33, Folder 1149)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1150)
- Oversize, 1897-1963; 6.25; (11 boxes)
  Oversize materials come from all four series and the papers are arranged in an order consistent with that in the original series. Boxes 34-35 hold papers of one size, Boxes 36-41 contain papers of larger dimensions, Box 43 holds poster-size materials, and Boxes 43-44 house lantern slides.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Subject
      - Fan/Hate Mail
        - General, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 1151-1152)
      - International Organizations
        - Artists International Association: Bulletin, 1937 Apr (Box 34, Folder 1153)
        - Spanish Civil War Relief: newsletters and newspapers, 1937 May 1 (Box 34, Folder 1154)
  - WRITINGS
    - Shorter Works: Articles
      - "Bereavement of Colonel Blimp," reprint from The Listener: printed version, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 1155)
      - "A Briton Explains British Doubts About Us," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1952 Jul 20 (Box 34, Folder 1156)
      - "Clues to an Understanding of Britain," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1949 Oct 30 (Box 34, Folder 1157)
      - "David Low Surveys His Seventy Years," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1961 Apr 2 (Box 34, Folder 1158)
      - "Famous Men at the Pencil Point," Evening Standard: printed version, 1931 Jan 26 (Box 34, Folder 1159)
      - "Fleet Street," Holiday: printed version, 1947 Jul (Box 34, Folder 1160)
      - "Gad, Sir, Col. Blimp Is Very Much Alive," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1943 Mar 7 (Box 34, Folder 1161)
      - "Low Deplores the Fog Over the Atlantic," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1946 Sep 22 (Box 34, Folder 1162)
      - "Low Looks at Hitler," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1944 Sep 3 (Box 34, Folder 1163)
      - "Mr. Low Reports on the UNO," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1946 Feb 10 (Box 34, Folder 1164)
      - "Mr. Low Takes the Stump," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1953 Oct 18 (Box 34, Folder 1165)
      - "My Sword Is the Drawing Pen," Palestine Post: printed version, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 1166)
      - "A Plea for 'the Cult of Personality,'" The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1956 Dec 2 (Box 34, Folder 1167)
      - "Portrait of the Master Race in the Dock," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1945 Dec 23 (Box 34, Folder 1168)
      - "These Vulgar Cartoons," Evening Standard: printed version, 1929 Dec 20 (Box 34, Folder 1169)
  - PUBLISHED DRAWINGS
    - Magazine Drawings
      - Collier's, 1939 Nov 18 (Box 34, Folder 1170)
      - The Exhibition Sketcher, 1906 Oct 3 (Box 34, Folder 1171)
      - The Illustrated Police Budget, 1900 Nov 24 (Box 34, Folder 1172)
      - The Lone Hand, 1913-14 (Box 34, Folder 1173)
      - The Lone Hand, 1914 (Box 34, Folder 1174)
      - The Sketcher, 1897 Dec (Box 34, Folder 1175)
      - The Spectator, 1910 Dec 19 (Box 34, Folder 1176)
    - Newspaper Drawings
      - "Low and I," Star, 1922-23 (Box 34, Folder 1177-79)
      - "Low & Terry," Evening Standard, 1932-34 (Box 34, Folder 1180-81)
      - Miscellany, 1942 Jul (Box 34, Folder 1182)
    - Works of Others
      - Hungerford, Cyrus, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1183)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Correspondence Lessons in Art
      - The National Press Association: lesson nos. 1-30, ca. 1903 (Box 35, Folder 1184-88)
      - The New York School of Caricature
        - General materials, ca. 1903 (Box 35, Folder 1189)
        - Lesson plate nos. 7, 10-17, ca. 1903 (Box 35, Folder 1190-92)
        - Lesson plate nos. 18, 21, 23, ca. 1903 (Box 35, Folder 1193)
        - Lesson plate nos. 24, 26-29, ca. 1903 (Box 35, Folder 1194-95)
        - Sketch, ca. 1904 (Box 35, Folder 1196)
    - Personal Press Clippings
      - Scrapbooks
        - Book no. 11: loose clippings, 1939 Oct 14 (Box 35, Folder 1197)
        - Book no. 12: loose clippings, part II, 1942 Apr 26 (Box 35, Folder 1198)
        - Book no. 13: loose clippings, 1946 (Box 35, Folder 1199)
        - Book no. 19 [obituaries of David Low], 1963 (Box 35, Folder 1200)
    - Works on Low
      - Hauser, Ernest O., "Gad, Sir, Here's Col. Blimp's Creator!": printed version, 1945 Nov 17 (Box 35, Folder 1201)
      - Lima, Herman, "O Poderoso Senhor Low": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1202)
      - "The Man Who Fought Hitler with His Pen": printed version, 1939 Oct 14 (Box 35, Folder 1203)
      - Moore, William, "Prince of Caricaturists": printed version, 1926 Jun 19 (Box 35, Folder 1204)
      - "Personalities and Powers": printed version, 1922 Mar 31 (Box 35, Folder 1205)
      - Thorogood, Horace, "How Low Works": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1206)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Subject
      - Contacts outside Great Britain
        - China: Chen, I-wan (Jack), part I, 1936 Nov 9 (Box 36, Folder 1207)
  - WRITINGS
    - Books
      - A Cartoon History of Our Times: book reviews, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 1208)
      - Lions and Lambs: book reviews, 1929 (Box 36, Folder 1209)
      - Low on the War: A Cartoon Commentary of the Years 1939-41: book reviews, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 1210)
      - Low's Autobiography: book reviews, 1956-57 (Box 36, Folder 1211)
      - Low's Political Parade: book reviews, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 1212)
      - Low's Russian Sketchbook: book reviews, 1932-33 (Box 36, Folder 1213)
      - Low's War Cartoons: Preface, "Garden of Gammon," published as "Various Shades of Liars in a Cartoonist's Dream," Sunraysia Daily: printed version, 1943 Dec 11 (Box 36, Folder 1214)
      - The Madde Designer: book reviews, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1215)
      - Years of Wrath: A Cartoon History 1939-45
        - Advertisements, 1946 Aug 22 (Box 36, Folder 1216)
        - Book reviews, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 1217)
    - Shorter Works
      - Articles
        - "The Changing Face of Humour," reprint from The Listener: printed version, 1938 Dec (Box 36, Folder 1218)
        - "Cult of Personality," The Press: printed version, 1957 Feb 9 (Box 36, Folder 1219)
        - "David Low Examines Lend-Lease Humor," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1945 Feb 4 (Box 36, Folder 1220)
        - "A Famous New Zealander": printed version, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 1221)
        - "I Believe...,": printed version, 1953 Nov 6 (Box 36, Folder 1222)
          See also: "Mr. Low Takes the Stump," Box 17, folders 736-37
        - "'Krokodil' and Russian Comic Art," The Listener: printed version, 1951 Mar 1 (Box 36, Folder 1223)
        - "A Lifetime of Low"
          - The Hindu: printed version, 1961 Apr 22/3 (Box 36, Folder 1224)
          - The Rhodesia Herald: printed version, 1961 Jun 2 (Box 36, Folder 1225)
          - The Sydney Morning Herald: printed version, 1961 May 13 (Box 36, Folder 1226)
        - "Low among the Americans"
          - The Advertiser: printed version, 1937 Jan 16 (Box 36, Folder 1227)
          - Evening Standard: printed version, 1936 Nov 14 (Box 36, Folder 1228)
          - The Illustrated Weekly of India: printed version, 1937 Jan 10 (Box 36, Folder 1229)
          - The Johannesburg Star: printed version, 1938 Dec 26 (Box 36, Folder 1230)
          - The Natal Advertiser: printed version, ca. 1937 (Box 36, Folder 1231)
          - The Sun News-Pictorial: printed version, 1937 Jan 23 (Box 36, Folder 1232)
          - The Telegraph: printed version, 1938 May 14 (Box 36, Folder 1233)
        - "The Low Down on Life in London Today," Sydney Telegraph: printed version, 1941 Jul 20 (Box 36, Folder 1234)
        - "Mr. Low Interviews Colonel Blimp," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1944 Apr 2 (Box 36, Folder 1235)
        - "Rise and Decline of Hitler--A Cartoon History," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1945 Apr 29 (Box 36, Folder 1236)
        - "This Is Why We Should Be Optimistic," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1950 Oct 15 (Box 36, Folder 1237)
      - Letters to the Editor: Cartoons
        - "The Morning After": part II, 1953 Jun 5 (Box 37, Folder 1238)
        - "The Patriots", 1936 Jul 27 (Box 37, Folder 1239)
  - PUBLISHED DRAWINGS
    - Defaced Clippings of Cartoons
      - Defaced Clippings of Cartoons, 1921-39 (Box 37, Folder 1240)
    - Graphics
      - Graphics, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1241)
    - Magazine Drawings
      - Double-page colour cartoons
        - "Into Battle by Low", 1955 May 28 (Box 37, Folder 1242)
        - "The Past Meets the Present", n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1243)
        - "To Winston, with Affectionate Birthday Greetings from His Old Castigator--Low", 1954 Nov (Box 37, Folder 1244)
      - "The War Memoirs of Winston Churchill," Life, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 1245)
      - Miscellany, 1920-63, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1246-48)
    - Newspaper Drawings
      - "Low's Topical Budget," Evening Standard, 1934-37 (Box 38, Folder 1249-60)
      - "Low's Topical Budget," Evening Standard, 1937-40 (Box 39, Folder 1261-74)
      - "Low's Topical Budget," Evening Standard (Box 40, Folder 1275-79)
      - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1280)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Biographical Materials
      - Churchill, Winston, "The Power of the Cartoon," Sunday Dispatch: printed version, 1940 Mar 3 (Box 40, Folder 1281)
      - Mock Trials, 1930-34 (Box 40, Folder 1282)
      - Photographs of David Low as they appeared in various magazines and newspapers: part II, 1935-50, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1283)
    - Personal Press Clippings
      - Scrapbooks
        - Book no. 14: loose clippings, part II, 1953 May 14 (Box 40, Folder 1284)
      - Loose clippings
        - 1910s-1930s, 1918-39, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1285)
        - 1940s-1960s, 1941-58 (Box 40, Folder 1286)
    - Works on Low
      - Abraham, A. M., "They Consider It a Privilege to Be Lampooned by Low," The Sunday Standard: printed version, 1955 Mar 13 (Box 40, Folder 1287)
      - Balslev-Jorgensen, "Jeg foler mig som Tilskuer sat paa en Sky...," Vestkysten: printed version, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1288)
      - Barker, Dudley, "The Life Story of Low"
        - Bulawayo Herald: printed version, 1950 Jan 10 (Box 40, Folder 1289)
        - Cape Argus: printed version, 1950 Feb 11 (Box 40, Folder 1290)
        - Daily Herald: printed version, 1950 Jan 10/11 (Box 40, Folder 1291)
        - The Johannesburg Star: printed version, 1950 Feb 11 (Box 41, Folder 1292)
      - Biagi, Enzo, "La terribile matita di un signore tranquillo"
        - Il Quotidiano Sardo: printed version, 1948 Jan 11 (Box 41, Folder 1293)
        - La Gazzetta del Popolo: printed version, 1948 Apr 3 (Box 41, Folder 1294)
      - Biagi, Enzo, "Tre uomini che son tre facce dell'Inghilterra," Gazzetta Veneta: printed version, 1947 Dec 1 (Box 41, Folder 1295)
      - "Birth of a Cartoon," Picture Post: printed version, 1938 Oct 22 (Box 41, Folder 1296)
      - Bradish, C. R., "Low's 50 Years of Cartooning," The Sydney Morning Herald: printed version, 1959 May 9 (Box 41, Folder 1297)
      - da Costa, R., "David Low: Slayer of Stuffed Goliaths,"
        - Saturday Night: printed version, 1948 Apr 17 (Box 41, Folder 1298)
        - The Sun Week-end Magazine: printed version, 1947 Mar 8 (Box 41, Folder 1299)
        - The Sunday Times Magazine: printed version, 1947 Apr 6 (Box 41, Folder 1300)
        - Dutch title "Gesprek met David Low," De Groew [?]: printed version, 1948 Aug 21 (Box 41, Folder 1301)
      - Davenport, Nicholas, "Sugar Candy Blimp," The New Statesman and Nation: printed version, 1943 Jun 26 (Box 41, Folder 1302)
      - "David Low," The Artist: printed version, 1940 Aug (Box 41, Folder 1303)
      - Driberg, Tom, "Unobtrusive Iconoclast: David Low, 'A Nuisance Dedicated to Sanity'"
        - The Leader: printed version, 1945 Aug 18 (Box 41, Folder 1304)
        - New Zealand Listener: printed version, 1945 Nov 2 (Box 41, Folder 1305)
      - Gall, Ian, "Cartoonist Who Foresaw the Years of Wrath," The Courier-Mail: printed version, 1949 Jul 30 (Box 41, Folder 1306)
      - Gammans, L. D., "King of the Blimps?," The Hornsey Journal: printed version, 1944 Feb 11 (Box 41, Folder 1307)
      - Hegedus, Adam de, "Low--the Giant Killer": printed version, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1308)
      - Holman, Dennis, "David Low, the Mild Character Whose Drawings Bite," John Bull: printed version, 1950 Feb 18 (Box 41, Folder 1309)
      - Innes, Guy, "The Mighty Mr. Low," The New York Times Magazine: printed version, 1941 Nov 30 (Box 41, Folder 1310)
      - Kinross, Lord, "Puck with a Pencil," Illustrated: printed version, 1950 Feb 4 (Box 41, Folder 1311)
      - Low, Caroline, "Low's First Studio in the Fowlhouse," Evening Standard: printed version, 1928 Jul 20 (Box 41, Folder 1312)
      - Owen, Frank, "David Low--World Famous Cartoonist": printed version, 1953 Oct 4 (Box 41, Folder 1313)
      - Reventlow, Chr. Ditlev, "Low's Pen spidder Beromthederne, Sandhederne, Dumhederne," Hjemmet: printed version, 1937 Sep 21 (Box 41, Folder 1314)
      - Sibi, Jean, "David Low: Caricaturist," reprinted from The Lone Hand: printed version, 1915 Oct 1 (Box 41, Folder 1315)
      - Taylor, Laurie, "Low in London," The Herald: printed version, 1949 Mar 12 (Box 41, Folder 1316)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Printed Materials, Miscellaneous
      - Air raid precautions materials, part II, 1940s (Box 42, Folder 1317)
  - LANTERN SLIDES
    - Lantern slides, n.d. (Box 43, Folder -)
    - Lantern slides, n.d. (Box 44, Folder -)